For a long time, I've always been the
friend to whip out her phone or camera
and start recording and capturing things
as they're happening. I love documenting
my life through spontaneous photos and
videos, and as I've recently entered my
mid-20s, I realized that there's no
better time to start capturing moments
than now. To me, vlogging is not about
portraying a perfect life. It's actually
about noticing the aesthetic in the
ordinary. While I'm still learning and
playing around with my personal method
of vlogging and capturing moments
cinematically, here is how you can start
capturing your life even if you're just
a girl with a phone and a busy schedule.
Let's get into it. First things first,
gear. You actually don't need that
$2,000 camera sitting in your Amazon
basket. If you do have cameras, which I
definitely have, they're about us.
They're designed to capture things
beautifully, and their job is to make
things look good. But, if I'm being
completely honest, you only really need
your phone to start. Let's talk about
using your phone to vlog. With general
flagship phones, these are the options
that you should use. I highly recommend
filming in 4K as it will capture many
more pixels in your video. And for
frames per second, I still really like
using 30 or 24 for the most natural
motion. The only thing that is really
important is to make sure that your lens
is clean. I know it sounds basic, but if
you have a blurry lens, things will just
not look good. Having your phone as your
main camera is a huge bonus, especially
because it's super easy to whip it out
from your pocket [music] and just
capture things really quickly. The
quality of the video is also something
that you'll never have to worry about.
If you're using your phone for vlogging,
there's a few pieces of equipment that I
really like to use. I always like to
make sure that I have a MagSafe case so
that I can stick on my Mophie tripod
stand so that I can set up my camera.
Or, I also recently got a magnetic and
suction mount so that I can mount my
phone to magnetic surfaces or stick it
onto flat surfaces as well. These will
allow you to get creative with your
angles, and when it comes to vlogging,
sometimes coming up with the most weird
angles is really great way to go about
making your video dynamic. Now, if you
do have cameras such as the DJI Osmo
Pocket 3, the Insta360 GO Ultra, or the
DJI Action 5 Pro, which are all cameras
that I really enjoy using on a daily,
you can make the most out of those
cameras by using them what they're best
for. My DJI Osmo Pocket 3 is the best
for capturing things really [music]
smoothly. It has a gimbal, and I really
enjoy using it when I'm just walking
around because it'll stay so smooth.
[music] It's also great for capturing
detail in shots and provides a pretty
narrow field of view so that I can
really focus on the detail in whatever
I'm shooting. I like to use my DJI
Action 5 Pro and the Insta360 GO Ultra
for more creative angles. And since they
have wide fields of view, I feel like
it's great for me to just set up the
camera, walk away from it, and you'll be
able to see so much of the scenery that
is around me. [music] Another big plus
side to using those cameras is that they
have the function to record in vlog
format, which allows you to play with
the color and honestly make all your
footage look so much more cinematic.
[music] Something that I have been
trying to use recently when filming with
my phone is the Blackmagic Cam app. This
app allows you to change settings in
your camera that you normally won't be
able to, like correcting white balance,
shutter speed, and adjusting your ISO as
well. It's also fun because it comes
with some built-in LUTs for you to
change what your footage looks like. If
you want to try to capture more
cinematic footage with your iPhone, I
would highly recommend playing around
with the Blackmagic Cam app. I've always
been really into photography and video,
so framing things comes pretty naturally
to me, but here are the basic rules that
you should follow. First of all, the
rule of thirds. Rule of thirds is
basically you split your screen into a
3x3 grid, and you have nine different
squares. Generally, when you're filming
things, you don't want to put yourself
dead center in the middle of the frame,
but because this is a sit-down and talk
video, it makes most sense to do that. I
really like to align myself to one of
the two lines over here. And when I'm
taking photos, I'm really mindful of how
much head space I have. For example, in
this clip that I took of my commute, you
can see the rule of thirds applied here.
[music] I'm framed at one of the lines
here, and then you could see the train
passing by in another way, and that adds
a lot of dimension to my [music] shot
and overall just makes it a little bit
more aesthetically pleasing. Another way
that I really like to make my videos a
little bit more cinematic is by changing
the angle. You can go high, you can go
low, you can go from side to side. It's
fun to always perceive things from a
different perspective than what you're
used to in real life. It's just a fun
way to keep things a little edgy and
different. Number three, let's talk
about lighting. Lighting is huge.
Lighting will make or break your
footage. Always make sure you have some
source of light coming at you or from
the sides of your face. It'll brighten
up the subject in your footage and make
the video quality the best it can be.
Usually, I try to avoid filming with
backlight because that'll just wash me
out. But, in day-to-day scenarios, when
you can't really control the light, just
be wary of where the sun is, and then
rotate your body to make sure that you
can get a good lighting situation.
>> [music]
>> Now, let's talk about filming in public.
I still get really self-conscious of
filming myself in public. I'm always
self-conscious of all the [music] eyes
that are staring at me when I pull my
camera out. I think that's super
natural. I'm someone who doesn't really
like to attract attention to myself, but
I love capturing the beauty in [music]
everyday moments. So, one thing that I
definitely had to get used to is getting
over the fear of being perceived. I'm
definitely more comfortable filming in
spaces that I am not a resident of. For
example, whenever I travel, it's super
easy for me to just capture footage and
vlog things because I know I'm not
staying there for a long time. But, if
I'm filming in my city, I'm always a
little bit self-conscious because I feel
like I might run into those people
again. The thing that helped me get over
the fear of being perceived is actually
just seeing the content [music] that I'm
capturing with my cameras. Every time I
return home to edit a video or just look
at the clips and photos that I've taken
throughout the day, I'm never thinking,
"Oh, I really embarrassed myself trying
to get this piece of footage." [music]
I'm usually thinking, "Oh, wow, I
actually really like the way that this
turned out." And putting myself in a
potentially embarrassing situation
[music] was actually so worth it. I've
captured countless cinematic memories
because of this mindset, and honestly,
the pros of me going out of my way
[music] to get a good clip outweigh the
public embarrassment that I may feel
when filming these clips. It definitely
is a mindset shift, and it gets easier
as you practice filming [music] in
public more frequently. And if it helps,
when you're documenting your life, your
main character is you. You can take
something that's boring and simple and
record it in a way that makes it
captivating. [music] Take your videos,
photos, take your content, and just post
it. I promise that you'll love looking
back at these memories. [music] Don't
forget to like and subscribe, and I'll
see you in my next video. Bye.